### Ajai Singh

\* +91 9928034789 | E-mail: ajai1619@gmail.com

30 years of experience bundled into A natural leader who commands respect from the team and has the ability to make most difficult and mundane targets look simple to be achieved. Sales, Operations, Training

What I bring on the table: Discipline, Indian geography and demography knowledge and experience. Team building and development, Large scale multilocation operations expertise, Logistics and reverse logistics execution.

Experience: From Brick and Mortar to current technologies. Farm Machinery, Office automation, Life Insurance, Food Retail, Hospitality. Food Delivery.

P&L accountability: With an eye on vision and core beliefs, strategic and tactical analysis, with special strength in execution are my forte.

### Work Experience

#### Zomato Media Pvt. Ltd.

### **Zonal Training Lead August 2018- To Date**

- Part of L&D team looking After States of Maharshtra, Gujarat, Goa, Madhya Pradesh for Delivery Partner Training
- Managing and developing City Training Lead and Regional Training Lead
- On ground execution of New Hire Training and refresher Training
- Content development to automate large scale > 10000 a month hiring and training
- Course Development and delivery of Team Leader training
- New City Launch team selection and Development
- Large scale execution project based training (Acquisition of Uber Eats, Covid-19 Contactless delivery)

# Oak Dew (Him and Kays Agro Pvt. Ltd.) Consultant –Business Development May 2017- May 2018

 A Well known Natural Spring Water in Upper Himalayas of Uttarakhand with amazing quality

- Sales and Marketing strategy to offer this water in the premium segment in Metros, Airlines, Modern trade
- Development of Packing and packaging, Collaterals
- Vendor development for Inputs, Reduced the input cost of raw material, Labour and Inward transportation by negotiation on order size and payment terms
- Created a retail network in Upper Himalayas to augur the locational advantage over Pan India Brands. Doing BTL and ATL activities to increase Sales
- Developed a cost effective supply chain self / out sourced and increased the efficiency and profitability per litre in Distribution

### V Resorts (Bliss Inns Pvt. Ltd.) <u>www.vresorts.in</u> Vice President – Operations – January 2014 –April 2017

- A startup company funded by VC's of repute the assignment includes setting up the operations, sales, training, procurement, maintenance and upgrade of existing properties
- Property selection and launching as per business requirements
- Delivering perfect Guest Delight
- Increasing the sales through presence in both online and offline space by optimum utilization of marketing budgets.
- Mentoring the employees for the career and personal growth.
- Developing a long term association with the vendors and Rural ecosystem around the properties as part of CSR.
- Ensuring the compliances for running the business

## Reliance Industries Ltd. – Retail as Head –NSO Training from October 2006 – December 2013

Planning, Managing and Executing the training for all roles in a new Store/Branch Opening.

- Joined as State Training Head Rajasthan in August 2006
- Promoted as Zone Head North West Zone March 2010
- Handled East and West Zone as Zone Head July 2010-October 2011
- Handled Fresh Food Academy Training October 2011 September 2012
- Recruiting, Developing and Mentoring a team of Trainers and Training Coordinators.
- Budgeting the Training investments for Effective Utilization of In-House and Outsourced Resources.
- Conducting sessions for New Leaders on Team Management, Business goals and Objectives, Operational Excellence.
- Working and delivering results on specific Business needs / projects to increase the profitability of the zone

# Tata AIG Life Insurance Co. Ltd., Jaipur as Head- Distribution Training and Development- Rajasthan from June 2004 - August 2006

- Looking after over all training and development of Agency Training in Rajasthan
- Regular nurturing and development of the trainers and increase their productivity and effectiveness.
- Training on Various investment and saving instruments viz. Mutual Funds, Equity Market, Insurance, Debt, Bonds

### **Other Assignments**

- 1. Allianz Bajaj Life Insurance Co. Ltd.- Jodhpur as Branch Manager from June 2003 to April 2004
- 2. Enkay Telecommunications (I) Ltd. March 2002 May 2003 as Business Head, Pune
- 3. Accord Communications Ltd 1999 to Feb 2002 as a Business Manager, Mumbai

1997 to 1999 as Sr. Manager Sales, Lucknow 1995 to 1997 as Sales Engineer, Lucknow 1993 to 1995 as Service Engineer, New Delhi

4. Escorts Ltd.,

1992-1993 as Area Sales Executive Lucknow 1989-1992 as Area Service Engineer, Bhopal

### Extra-Curricular Activities

- Elected member of Engineering society and University Student Union.
- Won 1st award and accolades in state level dramatics festival 1985.
- Very active athlete and sportsman winning at various levels of competitions in Swimming, Sprints, Football and Boxing.
- Travelled all over India on Motorbike covering all state capitals in 54 days.
- Music is my soul, and I am a happy soul I do spread happiness.
- Cooking various fare, innovatively, for office parties, gives me a kick.

### Education

- B. Tech from G.B.PantUniversity of Agriculture and Technology
- B. Sc. (Medical) from University of Lucknow

### Personal Details

Date of Birth : 08<sup>th</sup>.November.1963

Marital Status : Married Nationality : Indian

Address : 18/1101, Seawoods Estates, Sector 54,56,58

Palm Beach Road, Nerul. Navi Mumbai 400706

Impeccable References. On request.